

Bryan Yue

Software Developer

- 425-749-2741
- ✓ yue_bryan123@hotmail.com
- Seattle / WA / USA
- https://www.linkedin.com/in/bryanyue322/
- % https://github.com/byue

ABOUT ME

Experienced Developer with a strong track record designing lasting solutions, mentoring junior developers, and driving multi-team initiatives to completion.
Enjoys hikes and chess.

Tech Stack

- Cloud: Azure Ecosystem
- Languages: C#, C++, Java, Python
- Framework: .NET Core
- Storage: SQL, NoSQL
- Machine Learning: PyTorch, Pandas, Jupyter

SKILLS

8 / 10

API and System Design

9 / 10

Auto Remediation, Telemetry, and Metrics

7 / 10

Asynchronous and Concurrent Programming

10 / 10

Communication and Cross-Team Collaboration

9 / 10

Packaging, Deployment and CI Processes

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science *University of Washington*

2014 - 2018

Magna Cum Laude

University of Washington GPA: 3.89

Phi Beta Kappa Honor Society

University of Washington 2016 - Present

EXPERIENCE

Software Developer II

Microsoft | Redmond, WA | October 2019 - Present

Optimized on-premises cloud infrastructure and supported Azure-consistent scenarios.

- Designed support for IMDS, unblocking container orchestration scenarios.
- Reduced traffic 50x and decreased VM provisioning time 5 seconds with bulk VM metadata API backed by new .NET Core service.
- Reduced traffic 8x in compute critical path via VM agent protocol migration.

Software Developer

Bloomberg | New York City, NY | September 2018 – September 2019

Migrated petabytes of market data from legacy database to SamayDB within mission-critical 6-hour maintenance window.

- Reduced conversion times with caching and low-latency C++ techniques.
- Implemented recovery pathway for failed migration scenarios.
- Increased team productivity via automating environment setup and guides.

Machine Learning Engineer Intern

Kernel Labs | Seattle, WA | March 2018 – June 2018

Audio source separation with PyTorch. Achieved 82% test set accuracy.

- Created train, validation, and test sets with audio book web scraper
 - Visualized data with MFCC. Cleaned, and normalized data.
 - Trained BLSTM model with L2 regularization and dropout.